A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980 FA739G
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program Strategies in Reproductive Health and Population - Bangladesh (Reports 019830), 1992
- Reproductive Health/Reproductive Rights: Legal, Policy, and Ethical Issues (Reports 019831), 1992; Isaacs, Stephen L.; Freedman, Lynn P.
- Trip Report - Mexico: March 20-25 (Reports 019832), 1993; Isaacs, Stephen L.
- Epilogue: The Visiting Scholars Program (Through the Center for Women and Religion of the Graduate Theological Union) (Reports 019833), 1979; Waugh, Barbara
  PSJ/HRIC. Office Files of Mahmaz Ispahani.
- The U.S. Role in the World: New Priorities Abroad and New Voices at Home (Reports 019834), 1997
- African Intergovernmental Organizations: Human Rights Challenges (Reports 019835), 1998
- That 51 Percent: Ford Foundation Activities Related to Opportunities for Women (Reports 019836), 1974
  KCF - Office Files of Alison Bernstein.
- That 51 Percent Plus (Reports 019837), 1979; Pandolfi, Joyce Verhalen
- Evaluation of the Partnership for Higher Education in Africa (Reports 019838), 2004; Moja, Teboho; Reddy, Jairam; Whyte, Anne
- The Political Economy of Education: A Bibliography of Ford Foundation Supported Publications 1968-1980 (Reports 019839), 1981
- Status Report on the Education and Culture Program - Attached Memo from Susan V. Berresford (Reports 019840), 1983
- Created Equal: A Report on Ford Foundation Women's Programs (Reports 019841), 1986; Burns, Kathryn, 1959-; Rust, William
- And Gladly Teach: A Ford Foundation Report on the Urban Mathematics Collaboratives (Reports 019842), 1987; Nelson, Barbara Scott; Rust, William
- The Education and Culture Program's Math and Science Program (Reports 019843), 1988
- Task Force 2000: Creating Twenty-First Century Schools (Reports 019844), 1989
- The Ford Foundation and the Urban Poor in the 1950s (Reports 019845), 1993; O'Connor, Alice, 1958-
- Education and Culture 1994-1995 Biennium Budget and Program Paper (Reports 019846), 1993
- History of the Ford Foundation's Programmatic Philosophies 1950-1994: K-12 School Reform (Reports 019847), Wright, Charles Jr.
- Anti-Delinquency, Great Cities, Gray Areas (Reports 019848), 1987-1994; McCarthy, Kathleen D.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Pg. 36 is "Cut-Off"
- The Role of the Ford Foundation Fellowship Program for Minorities in the Production of Ph.D.s among Targeted Minority Groups and in Increasing the Representation of Members from These Minority Groups on the Faculties of Higher Education Institutions (Reports 019849), 1997; Harleston, Bernard W.
- Review of International Education Activities of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare; (Reports 019850), 1979; Krasno, Richard M.
  ID/LAC - Office Files of Richard M. Krasno.
- The Juvenile Justice And Delinquency Prevention Act (National Youth Alternative Project) (Reports 019851), 1975; Thennes, Mark A.
  National Affairs. Office Files of Esther Roditti Schachter.
- Family Policy (To the Members of the Committee on Public Policy and Social Organization) (Reports 019852), 1976; Chafkin, Sol H.; Roditti, Esther C.; Saario, Terry
  International Division/Education and Public Policy Division -- Office Files of Richard (Dick) Sharpe.
- A Report to the Trustees: Committee on Public Policy and Social Organization (Reports 019853), 1979
- Planning, Public Participation and Politics (Reports 019854), 1976; Gardner, John W. (John William), 1912-2002
- Next Steps in Planning for the Foundation's Future (Reports 019855), 1976; Heard, Alexander
- Implementation of the Agrarian and Educational Reforms in Peru (Reports 019856), 1976; Cleaves, Peter S.
- Foundations and Public-Private Ventures (Reports 019857), 1979; Thomas, Franklin A.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection.
- Minorities and Housing: Are the Doors Really Open (Reports 019858), 1979; Chandler, Robert
- Field Office Program Development Strategies in Education - Action Vs. Research (Reports 019859), undated; Sharpe, Richard S.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Date unknown
- Governmental Population Policies in West Africa (Reports 019860), 1971; Gwatkin, Davidson R.
- Cuba: 1998, Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 019861), Crahan, Margaret E.; Epstein, Dorothy
  PSJ/HRIC -- Office Files of Cristina Eguizabal.
- International Affairs Program Staff Retreat, Costa Rica --Rapporteur's Notes (Reports 019862), 1994; Hershkovitz, Michael
- Initial Guidance with Respect to the Tax Reform Act of (Reports 019863), 1970; Bell, David E., 1919-2000
  International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean -- Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files.
- OD Self-Study: Questions for Representatives, Report for Venezuela (Reports 019864), 1966
- General Reflections on a Visit to Argentina (Reports 019865), 1967; Adams, Richard N. (Richard Newbold), 1924-
- Basic Science in Brazil: Mid-1961, Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 019866), Harrison, George Russell
- Suggestions for Ford Foundation Support of Science and Technology in Argentina (Reports 019867), 1960; Kidd, Charles Vincent
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Pg. 8 missing from report
- Future Programs in Diplomacy, 1970-1975 (Reports 019868), 1969
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Author(s) unknown.
- Audio Cassette Technology (Reports 019869), 1973; Colle, Royal D.
  International Division/Asia & the Pacific - Manila, Philippines, Office Files.
- Tomorrow's Children: The Role of Nutritional and Environmental Stressors in the Learning and Behavior (Reports 019870), 1979; Lerner, Michael; Johnston, Cynthia
  National Affairs -- Cooney, Office Files of Thomas.
- The Influence of Health on Adolescents' Social Adjustment and Educational Achievement in a Residential Treatment Center: A Preliminary Report (Reports 019871), undated; Schwartz, David C.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. No Date of Publication
- Public/Private Enterprise in Britain and America, n.d. (1 of 2) (Reports 019872), undated; Stainsby, Charles
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;No Date of Publication
- Public/Private Enterprise in Britain and America, n.d. (2 of 2) (Reports 019873), undated; Stainsby, Charles
- Review of Evaluation and Research on U.S. Government: Domestic Nutrition Intervention Programs (Reports 019874), 1974; Becker, Jane R.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Pgs. 11-16 Missing from Report;Pgs. 45-51 Missing from Report.
- Study of Medical/Health Evaluations Performed on Juveniles in Placement: Final Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 019875), 1979; Schultz, Stephen R., 1960-; Margen, S.
- Report to Ford Foundation - Federal Programs in Nutrition with Special Emphasis on Programs Relating to Child and Maternal Health and Nutrition (Reports 019876), undated; Weingarten, Victor
- Health, Nutrition, Population Activities in Thailand, Apr 1, 1980 (Reports 019877), Simmons, Ozzie G.
- Community Development Corporations - New Instruments to Overcome Poverty (Reports 019878), 1972
- The Local Initiatives Support Corporation -- Community and Neighborhood Revitialization, Jun 1, 1980 (Reports 019879)
  Local Initiatives Support Corporation
- The Local Initiatives Support Corporation -- National Support for Local Development, Mar 25, 1980 (Reports 019880)
- Ford Foundation: Look at Conflict Resolution (Reports 019881), 1980; Jaffee, Sandy
- Report of the PPSO Humanistic Perspectives on Contemporary Society Task Force, Oct 10, 1980 (Reports 019882), Sharpe, Richard S.
- Conflict Resolution: Prospects for the Future -- Information Paper, n.d. (Reports 019883), undated
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Author(s) Unknown;No Date of Publication
- Law School Teaching of Legislation: A Report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 019884), undated; Dolan, Joseph P.
- National Affairs Programs - Status Report (Reports 019885), 1976; Ellis, James R.
- Go-Betweens for Social Change (Reports 019886), 1978; Sviridoff, Mitchell
- The Improvement of the System Within the System -- Notes on Ethos of American Liberal Reform (Reports 019887), 1976; Miller, William Lee
- Discussion: Basic Research Needs in Race and Ethnicity, Jan 25, 1974 (Reports 019888), Teper, Shirley
- One Nation, So Many Governments: The Ford Foundation and the Goals of Reform (Reports 019889), 1973; Danielson, Michael N.; Hershey, Alan M.; Bayne, John M.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection;Pg. 181 Missing from Report.
- Notes on BMW's Trip to New Delhi-Calcutta-Karachi-Beirut (Reports 019890), 1963; Webster, Bethuel M. (Bethuel Matthew), 1900-1989
  Overseas Development/International Training and Research - Office Files of John Howard
- Field Research Problems in Indonesia (Reports 019891), 1957; Goethals, Peter R.
- A University Program for the Study of American Foreign Policy Problems (Reports 019892), 1953; Johnson, Howard, 1941-
- Support of Training and Research for the Improvement of Technical Assistance Abroad (Reports 019893), undated; Thurber, Clarence E.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. No date of publicaton.
- Preliminary Report on Iraq (Reports 019894), 1952
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Author(s) Unknown.
  Overseas Development/International Training and Research - Office Files of Cleon O. Swayzee.
- Background Material on the International Training and Research - Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program (Reports 019895), 1961
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Author(s) Unknown
  Overseas Development/International Training and Research - Office Files of Cleon O. Swayzee
- International Training and Research Program Outline (Reports 019896), undated
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Author(s) Unknown. No date of publicaton.
- Enhancing Human Rights in Hispanic South America -- Retrospective and Prospect (Reports 019897), Farer, Tom J.
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Andean Region and the Southern Cone - Program Staff Files.
- Reproductive Health and Population: A Foundation Strategy for the 1990s (Reports 019898) (Box 898)
- Health Economics, Health Financing, and Health Needs of Poor Women, Children in India (Reports 019899), 1990; Berman, Peter A. (Box 898)
- Termination Report: The Lima Office (Reports 019900), 1991; Offenheiser, Raymond C.
- FY 1990 and FY 1991 Biennial Budget, Lima: April 1989 Program Reviews (Reports 019901)
- The Program in Peru - Report on Its Current Status (Reports 019902), 1964
  International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean - Office Files of Peter A. Fraenkel.
- Peru - Thursday, October 3 and After (Reports 019903), 1968; Fraenkel, Peter Adolf, 1923-2007
- A Program Strategy in Strengthening the Educational System of Peru (Reports 019904), 1964
- Guidelines for Visiting Professors Programs (Reports 019905), 1965
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Auhtor(s) Unknown.
- Overseas Development Self-Study, Peru (Reports 019906), undated
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Author(s) Unknown. Date of Publication Unknown.
- Educating Administrators for Education (Reports 019907), 1967; Brown, Charles E. (Charles Edward)
- Toward Priorities for Assistance in Agricultural Development (Reports 019908), 1966; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank); Hardin, Lowell S.
- The Ford Foundation's International Division (Reports 019909), 1966; Wilhelm, Harry E.
- The Office of the Secretary and General Counsel - Functions and Services (Reports 019910), 1983
  Office of the Secretary - General Office Files.
- Innovation: Individuals, Networks, Patronage (Reports 019911), 2006; Kotkin, Stephen
  Office of Program Management/Program Operations and Services - Assets Division - Tom, Office Files of Fred.
- Culture Programs in Asia: An Internal Review (Reports 019912), 1993
  Overseas Office - ASIA - Hanoi Field Office Files.
- Draft Paper on the History of the Ford Foundation's International Human Rights Program, Aug 17, 1994 (Reports 019913), Picken, Margo
- Program Activities in Vietnam (Reports 019914), 1993; Sidel, Mark; Zurbuchen, Mary Sabina
- The Reform Context for Foundation Programming in Vietnam, n.d. (Reports 019915), undated
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Author(s) Unknown;Date of Publication Unknown.
- Media, Modernization and the Market Economy -- China's Journalism in the 1990s (Reports 019916), 1993; Polumbaum, Judy
- Notes on the Interface Between Reproductive Health and Sustainable Development (Reports 019917), 1996; Atkin, Lucille C.; Conroy, Michael E.
- International Division -- Proposed Budget, Fiscal Year 1969. (Reports 019918), 1968
- Management Costs (Reports 019919), 1968
  Communications -- Program Staff Files (primarily Fred Friendly files).
- Washington, D.C. Newsroom (Reports 019920), 1971
- Improving Family Planning Program Management in the Developing Countries, May 7 (Reports 019921), 1974; Wickham, Robert S.
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific - Manila, Philippines Field Office Files.
- Rationale and Suggestions for Establishing a Population Planning Unit: Malaysia (Reports 019922), 1972; Saunders, Lyle; Hardee, J. Gilbert
  Population Program - Office Files of Tim Rice.
- Proposals for General Reserve Funding (Reports 019923), 1980
  Population Program - Office Files of Michael S. Teitelbaum.
- Right vs. Right: Immigration and Refugee Policy in the United States, Aug 1 (Reports 019924), 1980; Teitelbaum, Michael S.
- Trends and Prospects in World Population, Nov 1980 (Reports 019925), Teitelbaum, Michael S.
- An Inquiry into the Uses of Instructional Technology (Vol. I), Mar 1972 (Reports 019926), Armsey, James W., 1917-2008; Dahl, Norman C.
  Population Program - Office Files of William O. Sweeney.
- Saving Energy: An Idea for a Private-Sector Initiative, n.d. (Reports 019927), undated; Sviridoff, Mitchell
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Date of Publication Unknown.
  Education and Public Policy/Resources and the Environment - Program Staff Files.
- Energy: The Next Twenty Years (Reports 019928), undated; National Economic Research Associates
- Major Population Problems of the Next Decade -- the View from One Foundation, Apr 1980 (Reports 019929), Harkavy, Oscar
  Population Program/Urban Poverty - Office Files of Oscar Harkavy.
- Testimony Before the Task Force on Population Growth and Ecology (Reports 019930), 1972; Harkavy, Oscar
- Family Planning - World Programs (Reports 019931), 1970; Harkavy, Oscar (Box 898)
- Site Visit to Northside Preservation Commissioner, Jun 10, 1982 (Reports 019932), Mehreteab, Ghebre Selassie
  USIAP/Urban Poverty. Correspondence Files of Ghebre Selassie Mehreteab, 1982-1985.
- Survey of Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development in Belgium, n.d. (Reports 019933), undated; Franchmont, Paul
  International Division/Population. Program Staff Files.
- Some Aspects of Sampling Variances and Minimum Sample Size for a Social Demographic Study of Algerian Families (Reports 019934), 1966; Baird, James T., Jr.
- Activities Report (Reports 019935), 1966; Kelly, George H.
  International Division/Middle East and Africa - Tunis, Tunisia Field Office Files.
- Ecole Nationale D'Administration: The Library (Reports 019936), 1968; Urquidi, John; Lehman, Maxwell
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection.Pg. 19 Missing from Report.
- The Ford Foundation/Population Council North African Population Program in Retrospect: 1963-1975; (Reports 019937), Marcoux, Alain
- Annual Program Report - West Africa Regional Office, Part III: Population and Family Planning in West Africa, A Situation Report for (Reports 019938), 1969; Gwatkin, Davidson R.
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection. Some Pages in Report are Cut Off.
- What is the Population/Family Planning Field doing About Utilizing Research? (Reports 019939), 1973; Nagel, John S.
- Corporate Social Responsibility: A Report Prepared for the Ford Foundation (Reports 019940), 1982
  Program-Related Investments (PRI) - Administrative Files.
  Alexander Kouzmanoff and Associates, Architects
- The Fund For Private Assistance In International Development (PAID): An Assessment of Financial Condition and Long-term Business strategy (Reports 019941), 1989; Lanier, Catherine Bragg; Steinberg, James Braidly
- Equity Grant Review (Reports 019942), 1988; Brody Weiser Burns
  Brody Weiser Burns
- Administrative Reform Program for The Ministry of Health (Reports 019943), 1970
  International Division/MEA. Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, Field Office Files.
  Saudi Arabia
- The Administrative Reform Program, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. (Reports 019944), 1967
- Saudi Arabia - A Synopsis (Reports 019945), 1970
- Saudi Arabia Administrative Reform Program, Two Major Problems -- Approaches and Perceptions (Reports 019946), 1969
- The English Language Program of the Institute of Public Administration (Reports 019947), 1970; Mullins, Robert
- Requirements for Efficient Government Operation, Saudi Arabia (Reports 019948), 1971
- The Administrative Reform Program (Reports 019949), undated
- The Situation of Music, the Theater and the Plastic Arts in Portugal (Reports 019950), 1968; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Music Situation in Italy (Reports 019951), 1966; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Theater in the Federal Republic of Germany (Reports 019952), 1967; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Situation of the Plastic Arts in Spain (Reports 019953), 1969; D'Arschot, Ruby
- Music in the Netherlands, n.d. (Reports 019954), undated; D'Arschot, Ruby
- Norway -- The Situation of the Plastic Arts, Theatre, Music, Literature Cinema, Jul (Reports 019955), 1970; D'Arschot, Ruby
- Sweden -- The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Plastic Arts, Novelist, Cinema (Reports 019956), 1970; D'Arschot, Ruby
- Finland -- The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Cinema and the Plastic Arts (Reports 019957), 1970; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Cinema, and the Plastic Arts in Denmark, Apr (Reports 019958), 1970; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Music Situation in Great Britain (Reports 019959), 1968; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Situation of the Theatre in Great Britain (Reports 019960), 1968; D'Arschot, Ruby
- Situation of the Theater and Music in Switzerland (Reports 019961), 1969; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Situation of the Theater in Spain, (Reports 019962), 1969; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Official School of Cinematography in Spain, (Reports 019963), 1969; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Situation of Music in Spain (Reports 019964), 1969; D'Arschot, Ruby
- The Performing Arts Survey System, May 24 (Reports 019965), 1972; Lerner, J.B.
- The Comprehensive School Improvement Program (Reports 019966), 1971; Nachigal, Paul; Parkman, Francis, 1898-
- Leadership Development Program -- Staff Paper, Nov 10 (Reports 019967), 1971; Bohrson, Ralph G.; Newan, Brenda; Smith, Joshua L.
- National Council of the Arts -- Program Paper and Board of Trustees Draft Resolution, n.d. (Reports 019968), undated
- Thoughts on Future Northeast Leadership Development Program, Nov 12 (Reports 019969), 1971; Bohrson, Ralph G.; Paul A., Jr.
- Economic and Social Positions of the Artists and His Institutions. (Reports 019970), 1958
- Options for Opportunity Resources for the Arts, May 31 (Reports 019971), 1979; Zeigler, Joseph Wesley
- Strengthening Communications for Public Enlightenment, May 26 (Reports 019972), 1959; Armsey, James W., 1917-2008
- International Scientific, Educational and Cultural Exchange, May 27 (Reports 019973), 1959; Neilsen, Waldemar A
- Humanistic Scholarship -- Conference of Humanities. (Reports 019974), 1958
- A Proposal for a Program in the Arts of National Scope, Jan 4 (Reports 019975), 1960; McPeak, William Wallace
- The Ford Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting -- September 28-29, 1956, Nov 21 (Reports 019976)
- The Cost of Supplies and Equipment as a Manageable Expense for Biomedical Research, May 13 (Reports 019977), 1975; Loupos, John
- Minorities and Mathematics, Apr (Reports 019978), 1981; Coleman, Joan E.
- Ford Foundation Conference on Minorities and Mathematics (Reports 019979), 1980; Sullivan, Oona
- Japanese-American Teacher Exchange Program (Reports 019980), 1967; Feldman, Marvin J.